Guide to the James Rowland Angell, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1921-1937; Series I
  - Sheffield Scientific School
    - Dean and Assistant Dean (Box 172, Folder 1828)
    - Directorship (Box 172, Folder 1829-1830)
    - Minutes, 1928-1937 (Box 172, Folder 1831)
    - Rules for conduct (Box 173, Folder 1832)
    - Science and Management (Box 173, Folder 1833)
    - Summer school for engineering teachers (Box 173, Folder 1834)
  - Shem (Box 173, Folder 1835)
  - Sheppard, Walter B. (Box 173, Folder 1836)
  - Sherrill, Charles, Sherrill Lectureship (Box 173, Folder 1837)
  - Sherrill, Henry Knox (Box 173, Folder 1838)
  - Shoop, Max, American University in China Project (Box 173, Folder 1839)
  - Si-Sk (Box 173, Folder 1840)
  - Sigma XI (Box 173, Folder 1841-1842)
  - Silliman Lectureship (Box 173, Folder 1843-1845)
  - Sim (Box 174, Folder 1846)
  - Smith (Box 174, Folder 1847-1848)
  - Smith, Robert Seneca (Box 174, Folder 1849)
  - Sn (Box 174, Folder 1850-1851)
  - Snow, Alpheus Henry Prize (Box 174, Folder 1852)
  - Social Sciences Department (Box 174, Folder 1853-1854)
  - Society for the Promotion of Engineering Education (Box 174, Folder 1855)
  - Sociology Department (Box 174, Folder 1856)
  - Sophomore class student counselors (Box 174, Folder 1857)
  - Sp (Box 175, Folder 1858-1859)
  - Spalding, Jesse, Memorial Scholarship (Box 175, Folder 1860)
  - Spanish, Italian Department (Box 175, Folder 1861)
  - Spaulding, Frank E. (Box 175, Folder 1862)
  - Speck, William A. (Box 175, Folder 1863)
  - Spingold, Nate B. (Box 175, Folder 1864)
  - Spring vacation (Box 175, Folder 1865)
  - Spykman, Nicholas J. (Box 175, Folder 1866)
  - Squibb Fellowship Foundation (Box 175, Folder 1867)
  - St (Box 175, Folder 1868)
  - Standard Brands Incorporated (Box 175, Folder 1869)
  - Stanford University (Box 175, Folder 1870)
  - State Medical Center (Box 175, Folder 1871)
  - Ste (Box 175, Folder 1872)
  - Steiner, Gotthold (Box 175, Folder 1873)
  - Sterling Bequest (Box 176, Folder 1874-1875)
  - Sterling Fellowship (Box 176, Folder 1876-1877)
  - Sterling Memorial Buildings (Box 176, Folder 1878)
  - Sterling Professorship (Box 176, Folder 1879-1880)
  - Sterling Scholarship Fund (Box 176, Folder 1881)
  - Sterling Trustees (Box 176, Folder 1882)
  - Sti (Box 176, Folder 1883-1884)
  - Stimson, Henry L., London Naval Treaty (Box 176, Folder 1885)
  - Stoeckel, Ellen Battell (Box 176, Folder 1886)
  - Stokes, Anson Phelps (Box 176, Folder 1887)
  - Strathcona Fund (Box 176, Folder 1888)
  - Stresemann, Erwin (Box 176, Folder 1889)
  - Stuart, George Jr. (Box 176, Folder 1890)
  - Student drinking, Prohibition of (Box 177, Folder 1891-1892)
  - Student fraternities, clubs (Box 177, Folder 1893)
  - Student Friendship Fund (Box 177, Folder 1894)
  - Student Glee Club, Bartholomew, Marshall M. (Box 177, Folder 1895)
  - Student government (Box 177, Folder 1896)
  - Student meetings (Box 177, Folder 1897)
  - Students, Dean of, Discipline, morale, dancing, motor cycles (Box 177, Folder 1898)
  - Su (Box 177, Folder 1899-1902)
  - Sugar investigation, Professors Henderson and Haggard (Box 177, Folder 1903)
  - Sumner, William Graham Memorial (Box 177, Folder 1904)
  - Swan, Thomas W. (Box 177, Folder 1905)
  - Swarthmore College (Box 177, Folder 1906)
  - Swedish Crown Prince (Box 177, Folder 1907)
  - T-Tg (Box 178, Folder 1908-1913)
  - Taft, Horace D. (Box 178, Folder 1914)
  - Taft, Robert A. (Box 178, Folder 1915)
  - Taft, William Howard (Box 178, Folder 1916)
  - Tarbell, Frank Fund (Box 178, Folder 1917)
  - Teachers' loyalty oaths (Box 178, Folder 1918)
  - Teaching load (Box 178, Folder 1919)
  - Teaching positions, Yale men recommended for (Box 178, Folder 1920)
  - Terry, Dwight H. Fund (Box 179, Folder 1921)
  - Terry, Edmund R. Terry, Marjorie Jane (Box 179, Folder 1922)
  - Th (Box 179, Folder 1923-1924)
  - Thacher, Thomas Day (Box 179, Folder 1925)
  - Theological Seminaries Conference, 1926 (Box 179, Folder 1926)
    See also: box 18, folder 196
  - Thompson-Starrett Foundation (Box 179, Folder 1927)
  - Thorndike, Edward L. (Box 179, Folder 1928)
  - Ti (Box 179, Folder 1929)
  - Time Magazine (Box 179, Folder 1930)
  - Titles of university personnel (Box 179, Folder 1931)
  - To (Box 179, Folder 1932-1933)
  - Tommers, Bernard, Long Point Camp (Box 179, Folder 1934)
  - Tompkins (Ray) Memorial Greist Tract (Box 180, Folder 1935)
  - Tornquist (Carlos A.) Collection, Sterling Memorial Library (Box 180, Folder 1936)
  - Tr-Ts (Box 180, Folder 1937)
  - Traffic (Box 180, Folder 1938)
  - Traffic (Motor Vehicle) Committee Conference, 1924 April 9-11 (Box 180, Folder 1939)
  - Transportation (Box 180, Folder 1940-1946)
  - Treasurer's Office (Box 181, Folder 1947-1948)
  - Trinity College (Box 181, Folder 1949)
  - Trumbull, John H. (Box 181, Folder 1950)
  - Tu (Box 181, Folder 1951-1954)
  - Tuberculosis cure, Mathewson, George T. (Box 181, Folder 1955)
  - Tuition (Box 181, Folder 1956)
  - Tutorial system (Box 181, Folder 1957)
  - Tutoring Schools, Committee on (Box 181, Folder 1958)
  - Tuttle, Henry Emerson (Box 181, Folder 1959)
  - Tuttle, Morehouse and Taylor (Box 181, Folder 1960)
  - Typhoid (Box 181, Folder 1961)
  - U (Box 182, Folder 1962-1969)
  - Undergraduate Residential Quadrangles, Dormitories
    See: Undergraduate Colleges
  - Undergraduate Colleges
    - Berkeley (Box 183, Folder 1970-1971)
    - Branford (Box 183, Folder 1972)
    - Calhoun (Box 183, Folder 1973)
    - Davenport (Box 183, Folder 1974)
    - Timothy Dwight (Box 183, Folder 1975)
    - Timothy Dwight Fellows (Box 183, Folder 1976)
    - Timothy Dwight, Letters regarding headmaster of (Box 183, Folder 1977)
    - Jonathan Edwards Pierson (Box 183, Folder 1978)
    - Pierson (Box 183, Folder 1979)
    - Pierson, Letters regarding headmaster of (Box 183, Folder 1980)
    - Saybrook (Box 183, Folder 1981-1982)
    - Silliman (Box 183, Folder 1983)
    - Trumbull (Box 183, Folder 1984)
    - Trumbull, "The Trumbullian" (Box 183, Folder 1985)
    - General correspondence (Box 184, Folder 1986-1992)
    - Aldrich, M.P., Letters of (Box 184, Folder 1993-1994)
    - Applications for positions (Box 184, Folder 1995)
    - Athletic proposal, Comments on (Box 184, Folder 1996)
    - Committee on the Bursary Plan in the Colleges (Box 184, Folder 1997)
    - Committee on the Colleges (Box 184, Folder 1998)
    - Committee on the Development of Intramural Athletics (Box 184, Folder 1999)
    - Committee on the Development of Intramural Athletics (Box 185, Folder 2000)
    - Committee on Student Affairs (Box 185, Folder 2001)
    - Committee to Consider the Allocation of Dormitories Outside the New Colleges (Box 185, Folder 2002)
    - Council of Masters (Box 185, Folder 2003)
    - Council of Masters, minutes, 1932-1937 (Box 185, Folder 2004-2008)
    - Council of Masters, Committee on Distribution of Students to the Colleges (Box 185, Folder 2009-2011)
    - Council of Masters, Committee on the General Problems of the Religious and Spiritual Interests of the Students (Box 185, Folder 2012)
    - Council of Masters, Committee on Relations between the Fraternities and the Colleges (Box 185, Folder 2013)
    - Council of Masters, Committee on Relations between the Fraternities and the Colleges (Box 186, Folder 2014)
    - Council of Masters, Committee on Relations of Self-supporting Students with the Colleges (Box 186, Folder 2015)
    - Dining halls (Box 186, Folder 2016)
    - Dormitory rules (Box 186, Folder 2017)
    - Fellows (Box 186, Folder 2018)
    - Harkness, Edward S. (Box 186, Folder 2019-2024)
    - Inter-college athletics (Box 186, Folder 2025-2026)
    - Masters (Box 187, Folder 2027)
    - Miscellaneous reports on undergraduate reorganization (Box 187, Folder 2028-2029)
    - Pamphlets on the Colleges (Box 187, Folder 2030)
    - President Angell's trip to England to study the residential colleges of Cambridge, Oxford and St. Andrews (Box 187, Folder 2031)
    - Student chairmen and captains (Box 187, Folder 2032)
    - Student convocation (Box 187, Folder 2033)
    - Student Council, College and Sheffield (Box 187, Folder 2034)
    - Student drinking (Box 187, Folder 2035-2036)
    - Student fees and charges (Box 187, Folder 2037)
    - Student fraternities, clubs, etc. (Box 187, Folder 2038-2040)
    - Student fraternities, clubs Gamma Alpha (Box 187, Folder 2041)
    - Student fraternities, clubs, etc. Representatives of junior fraternities and Sheffield societies (Box 187, Folder 2042)
    - Student weekend exodus (Box 187, Folder 2043)
  - Undergraduate Faculty of Arts and Sciences
    - Committee on the Improvement of Scholarship (Box 188, Folder 2044-2045)
    - Committee on Rules and Regulations (Box 188, Folder 2046)
    - Committee on Schedules (Box 188, Folder 2047-2050)
    - Committee on Undergraduate Activities (Box 188, Folder 2051-2052)
    - Committee on Undergraduate Course of Study (Box 188, Folder 2053)
    - Committee on Undergraduate Catalogue (Box 188, Folder 2054)
    - Committee on Make Survey of Curriculum and Stabilization of Faculty (Box 188, Folder 2055)
    - Coordination of undergraduate courses (Box 189, Folder 2056)
    - Executive Committee (Box 189, Folder 2057)
    - Executive Committee, minutes (Box 189, Folder 2058)
    - Latin requirement (Box 189, Folder 2059-2061)
    - Minutes (Box 189, Folder 2062-2063)
    - Undergraduate instruction (Box 189, Folder 2064)
    - Undergraduate literary activities (Box 189, Folder 2065-2066)
  - Unitarian Conference (Box 190, Folder 2067)
  - Unitarian Layman's League (Box 190, Folder 2067)
  - United States Naval Academy (Box 190, Folder 2068)
  - United States Naval Academy, Cotton, Molton A. (Box 190, Folder 2069)
  - United Workers' Boys Club (Box 190, Folder 2070)
  - Upsala College, Dibble, L.A. (Box 190, Folder 2071)
  - V (Box 191, Folder 2072-2077)
  - Valentine, Alan C. (Box 191, Folder 2078)
  - Vanity Fair (Box 191, Folder 2079)
  - Van Volkenburgh, Mrs. Thomas (Box 191, Folder 2080)
  - Vincent, George E. (Box 191, Folder 2081)
  - Visual education (Box 191, Folder 2082)
  - Vocational guidance, Jennings, I.G. (Box 191, Folder 2083)
  - Vollbehr, Otto H.F. (Box 191, Folder 2084)
  - W (Box 192, Folder 2085-2086)
  - Walden, P.T. (Box 192, Folder 2087)
  - Walker, Williston (Box 192, Folder 2088)
  - Walker, Williston, Memorial Service for (Box 192, Folder 2089)
  - Warn-War (Box 192, Folder 2090)
  - War-Was (Box 192, Folder 2091)
  - Was (Box 192, Folder 2092)
  - Was-Wau (Box 192, Folder 2093)
  - War debts (Box 192, Folder 2094)
  - War Department Conference, 1922 November 16-18 (Box 192, Folder 2095)
  - War Memorial, War Record-Yale (Box 192, Folder 2096-2097)
  - Ward, Frederick A. Estate (Box 192, Folder 2098)
  - Warren, Charles (Box 192, Folder 2099)
  - We (Box 193, Folder 2100)
  - Weigand, Herman J. (Box 193, Folder 2101)
  - Wel (Box 193, Folder 2102)
  - Welch, Lewis S. (Box 193, Folder 2103)
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley Conference, 1924 October 11 (Box 193, Folder 2104)
  - Wells, Frederick Latimer Memorial Fund (Box 193, Folder 2105)
  - Wes (Box 193, Folder 2106)
  - Wesleyan University (Box 193, Folder 2107)
  - Western Union Telegraph Company (Box 193, Folder 2108)
  - Wh (Box 193, Folder 2109-2110)
  - Whitridge, Arnold (Box 193, Folder 2111)
  - Wi (Box 193, Folder 2112)
  - Wi (Box 194, Folder 2113)
  - Will (Box 194, Folder 2114-2115)
  - Wils (Box 194, Folder 2116-2118)
  - Winternitz, Milton C. (Box 194, Folder 2119)
  - Wo (Box 195, Folder 2120-2126)
  - Wolfers, Arnold (Box 195, Folder 2127)
  - Woolley, Helen T. (Box 195, Folder 2128)
  - Woolsey Hall (Box 195, Folder 2129)
  - World Court (Box 195, Folder 2130-2132)
  - Wr-Wy (Box 195, Folder 2133)
  - XYZ (Box 196, Folder 2134-2137)
  - Yale Alumni Weekly
    - General correspondence, 1921-1928 (Box 196, Folder 2138-2139)
    - General correspondence, 1933-1937 (Box 196, Folder 2140-2141)
    - University advertisement pages (Box 197, Folder 2142)
    - Yale plates (Box 197, Folder 2143)
  - Yale Budget Drive (Box 197, Folder 2144)
  - Yale Club, New York (Box 197, Folder 2145)
  - Yale College
    - 1921-1937 (Box 197, Folder 2146-2151)
    - Board minutes, Board of Permanent Officers, 1922-1937 (Box 197, Folder 2152-2153)
    - Board minutes, General Faculty, 1925-1937 (Box 198, Folder 2154-2156)
    - Concentration plan (Box 198, Folder 2157)
    - Course elections (Box 198, Folder 2158)
    - Deanship (Box 198, Folder 2159-2160)
    - Faculty Committee on Elections (Box 198, Folder 2161)
    - Faculty Committee on Examinations (Box 198, Folder 2162)
    - General needs of (Box 198, Folder 2163-2164)
  - Yale Daily News (Box 198, Folder 2165-2168)
  - Yale, Elihu (Box 199, Folder 2169)
  - Yale Engineering Association (Box 199, Folder 2170-2171)
  - Yale Engineering Association, East Lyme Summer Camp (Box 199, Folder 2172)
  - Yale Engineering Association, Newsletters and reports (Box 199, Folder 2173)
  - Yale graduate reading lists (Box 199, Folder 2174)
  - Yale-In-China (Box 199, Folder 2175-2179)
  - Yale-In-China, "XYZ" Foreign Missions Group (Box 200, Folder 2180)
  - Yale name, Protection of (Box 200, Folder 2181)
  - Yale-New Haven, Committees on Conference re; tax matter (Box 200, Folder 2182)
  - Yale-New Haven, Committees on Taxation (Box 200, Folder 2183)
  - Yale-New Haven, Mayor's Committee on Taxation, Swan-Fisher-Bushner (Box 200, Folder 2184-2186)
  - Yale Political Union (Box 200, Folder 2187)
  - Yale Publishing Association, Proposed scientific magazine (Box 200, Folder 2188-2189)
  - Yale Review (Box 200, Folder 2190)
  - Yale Review, Special Corporation Committee (Box 200, Folder 2191)
  - Yale Review, Special Corporation Committee (Box 201, Folder 2192)
  - Yale Scientific Journal (Box 201, Folder 2193)
  - Yale Song (Box 201, Folder 2194)
  - Yale Tapestries, Sandwich Collection (Box 201, Folder 2195)
  - Yale Union (Box 201, Folder 2196)
  - Yale University Press (Box 201, Folder 2197-2199)
  - Yale University Press, pamphlets (Box 201, Folder 2200)
  - Yale Young Men's Christian Association, Dwight Hall (Box 201, Folder 2201)
  - Yale Young Men's Christian Association, Dwight Hall (Box 202, Folder 2202-2203)
  - Yale Young Men's Christian Association, Reverend E. Fay Campbell (Box 202, Folder 2204)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, National (Box 202, Folder 2205)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, New Haven (Box 202, Folder 2206)
  - Zavoico, Colonel V.S. (Box 202, Folder 2207)
  - Zoology Department (Box 202, Folder 2208)
  - Zoology Department, Professor George A. Baitsell (Box 202, Folder 2209)
  - Zoology Department, Professor R.G. Harrison (Box 202, Folder 2210)
  - Zoology Department, Vivarium (Box 202, Folder 2211)
  - Inauguration of Angell Register (Box 203)